Resistance has a code name
Anthropoid is a history, thriller, war film directed by Sean Ellis.
In December 1941, Czech soldiers Jozef Gabčík and Jan Kubiš parachute into their
occupied homeland to assassinate Nazi officer Reinhard Heydrich.
Jan Kubiš, played by Jamie Dornan.
Josef Gabčík, played by Cillian Murphy.
Marie Kovárníková, played by Charlotte Le Bon.
Lenka Fafková, played by Anna Geislerová.
Adolf Opálka, played by Harry Lloyd.
Jan Zelenka, played by Toby Jones.
Anthropoid is a 2016 war film directed by Sean Ellis and starring Cillian Murphy, Jamie Dornan, Charlotte Le Bon, Anna
Geislerová, Harry Lloyd, Toby Jones and Marcin Dorocinski, It was written by Ellis and Anthony Frewin.
It depicts Operation Anthropoid, the assassination of Reinhard Heydrich by exiled
Czechoslovak soldiers Jozef Gabčík and Jan Kubiš in World War II.
It was released on 12 August 2016 in the United States and
9 September 2016 in the United Kingdom.
The film explores themes of assassination, nazi,
germany, world war ii, prague, czech republic.
The tone is intense.